sonymusic.com 2019-12-25

# Privacy Policy | Sony Music

Effective Date 01/01/2020

This Privacy Policy describes our policies on the collection, use and disclosure of your information in connection with your use of our websites, online and offline services, and emails (“Site” or “Sites”). Sony Music Entertainment (“Sony Music”) is a wholly owned subsidiary of Sony Corporation of America. Information collected on the Sites may be used in the manner described below by Sony Music Entertainment, our labels, agents, subsidiaries, trusted partners (such as artists and artist management) and affiliates acting on our behalf (collectively, “Sony Music”). When used herein, the terms “we”, “us” and “our” refer to Sony Music.  When this Privacy Policy uses the term “personal information,” we mean information that identifies or is reasonably capable of identifying or being associated with a particular individual, such as full name, street address, telephone number or email address.

We encourage you to review the entire Privacy Policy. Please click on any of the links below to review that particular section.

* * *

* * *

**Collection and Use of Personal Information**

We may collect the following categories of personal information from you:

  * Contact information, including name, email address, street or mailing address and telephone or mobile phone number
  * Billing information, including billing address, order details and other commercial information 
  * Demographic information, including age, date of birth, gender, interests, country and zip code
  * Unique identifiers, including user name and password
  * Preference and other information, including product wish lists, order history and marketing & music preferences  
  * Geolocation information, including your actual or approximate location (for example, from the IP address of your device or computer)
  * Photos and videos that you submit on our Sites
  * Internet and other electronic network activity

We or one of our trusted partners may use this information for the following business purposes:

  * Send you requested updates and newsletters about an artist, type of music or related special offers
  * Send you requested product or service information
  * Send a one-time email or e-card to your friends upon your request when you provide their email address
  * Fulfill your order
  * Send you an order confirmation
  * Respond to customer service requests, questions and concerns
  * Administer your account, including managing your preference center
  * Process information submitted with a job application
  * Send you marketing communications
  * Administer promotions and sweepstakes you enter and notify you of the results
  * Improve our marketing efforts
  * Maintain and improve our Sites, content, products and services
  * Conduct research and analysis
  * Display or promote content based upon your location and/or interests
  * Provide location services such as “tagging” and “check-in”
  * Maintain the security and effective functioning of our Sites and your accounts
  * Address our compliance and legal obligations and exercise our legal rights

We use cookies, web beacons and similar technologies to automatically collect internet and other electronic network activity, including information about your computer as you browse our Site(s).  We and our business partners may automatically collect information as you browse our Site(s) such as connection information (including the domain name and Internet Service Provider), browser type and version, mobile device ID, cell phone carrier, operating system and device type, average time spent on our Site(s), pages viewed, traffic to and from the websites, information accessed, the Internet Protocol (IP) address you use to connect to the Internet and related geographical information about your computer or mobile device, and advertising data and other standard weblog information. Such information is sometimes referred to as web analytics and/or clickstream data.

When you provide us with personal information about your contacts we will only use this information for the specific purpose for which it is provided.  

If you believe that one of your contacts has provided us with your personal information and you would like to request that it be removed from our database, please [click here](https://www.sonymusic.com/feedback/).

_Other Sources of Information_

We may receive information about you from other sources and may combine this data with information we already have about you, including:

  * **Artists** : such as marketing data from a new or partnering artist that is integrated with information we already have about you to create a more tailored fan experience;
  *  **Business Partners** : such as contest providers and other promotional partners, sub-contractors in technical, payment and delivery services, advertising networks, analytics providers and others who enable sign-on functionality and social network integration;
  *  **Publicly-available databases** ;
  *  **Other Applications** : such as music/video streaming sites and social media platforms; and
  *  **Digital Service Providers** : if you choose to use features on our Sites (such as pre-save campaigns) that connect to your online profiles or social media accounts, we may collect any information that you permit through your settings on those connected accounts.

This information helps us to update, expand and analyze our records, identify new customers and provide content and services that may be of interest to you.

_Monitoring and Fraud Prevention_

To help protect you and others, we monitor use of the Sites and we use the information we collect, including personal information, to identify fraudulent activities and transactions; prevent abuse of and investigate and/or seek prosecution for any potential threats to or misuse of the Sites; ensure compliance with the applicable terms of service and this privacy policy; investigate violations of or enforce these agreements; and otherwise to protect the rights and property of Sony Music, its partners and customers.  Monitoring may result in the collection, recording, and analysis of online activity or communications through the Sites, and you consent to this monitoring by using the Sites.  If you do not consent to these conditions, you must discontinue your use of the Sites.

_Retention_

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active and as needed to provide you services.  We will use and retain your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes and enforce our agreements.

We enable you to create a profile for accessing blogs or online communities for sharing information such as messages, photos and videos.  Please note that we cannot control the actions of others with whom you may choose to share your pages and information.  We may also enable you to post content from some of our Sites to your profile on other social networks.  You can access these services from our Sites using Facebook Connect, Twitter, or other Open ID providers.  These services will authenticate your identity and allow you to post and share certain personal or other information with that site.  Please be aware that the privacy policy of that site will apply to any content you provide them in these instances.  We do not allow these services to provide any personal information or content back to our Sites or your profile with us unless you agree.  To request removal of your personal information from our blog or community forum, [contact us here](https://www.sonymusic.com/feedback/).  If we are unable to remove your personal information, we will respond to your request with the applicable reasons.

Widgets – Our Site(s) may include interactive mini-programs that provide specific services from another company (e.g., displaying digital news feeds, playing music, “liking” or sharing content, etc.), often referred to as widgets.  You may have the opportunity to submit personal information, such as your email address, for collection through a widget.  A widget may also use browser or Flash cookies and/or collect clickstream and usage data. Information collected by a widget is governed by the privacy policy of the company that created it.

**Transactions**

You may purchase artists’ music or merchandise from some of our Site(s) or our Artists’ Site(s), in which case you will be directed to an externally hosted web page or site to complete your transaction.  These sites will be clearly identified and link to their own privacy policies so you know which company is collecting your personal information.  You should refer to those policies for any privacy-related concerns regarding your purchase.

**Information Sharing**

We will only share your personal information with others as described in this Privacy Policy.  We may provide your personal information to companies that help us with our business activities (e.g. shipping or processing an order, assisting us in Site operations, providing customer service, delivering email newsletters, etc.) or that assist us in improving our products, content, services or advertising.  These companies are authorized to use your personal information only as necessary to provide these services.

We may also share your personal information:

  * With Sony Music affiliates and representatives of our current recording artists
  * With affiliated Sony Group companies (i.e. any company in which Sony Corporation of America owns, directly or indirectly, 50% or more of its outstanding shares and any company with the name “SONY” as part of its trade name)
  * With reputable partners in whose products or services we think you may have an interest, with your prior consent to do so
  * With representatives of former recording artists, who will be advised in advance that your consent is required for continued use
  * As required by law, such as to comply with a subpoena or similar legal process
  * When we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud or respond to a government request
  * In connection with a corporate change including a merger, acquisition or sale of assets
  * To any other party with your prior consent to do so

**Choice/Opt-Out**

_Email and Newsletter Preferences_

You may choose to stop receiving newsletters, updates or marketing emails by following the unsubscribe instructions included in such emails.  Some Sites also allow you to change your email preferences within your online profile or by contacting us [here](https://www.sonymusic.com/feedback/).

_Interest-based Advertising_

We partner with other companies to manage our advertisements.  We or our partners may use cookies or similar technologies in order to provide you advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests on our Sites and other sites, and across your different devices.  If you wish to opt out of interest-based advertising please check your browser settings or if located in the European Union click [here](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/) for additional information.  

_Mobile Marketing_

If you choose to join a mobile marketing list, please be aware that there are usually costs associated with receiving SMS (text) or MMS (multimedia) messages depending on your wireless carrier and plan.  You should check with your mobile carrier to determine what charges apply before signing up to receive our updates via your mobile phone.  If you would like to stop receiving messages from us on your mobile phone, please reply to the message with “STOP.”  You may also contact your wireless carrier for additional information on receiving or stopping mobile messages.

We may also send you push notifications from time-to-time in order to update you about any events or promotions that we may be running.  If you no longer wish to receive these types of communications, you may turn them off at the device or application level, as applicable.  To ensure you receive proper notifications, we will need to collect certain information about your device such as operating system and user identification information.

_Geolocation_

If you have previously enabled your computer or mobile device to send us location information, you may be able to opt-out from further allowing us to access such information by changing the settings on your computer or mobile device or by uninstalling the application.

**Tracking Technologies**

We and our business partners use cookies and other technologies such as web beacons to keep track of your visits, preferences and profile information.  This information is used to make our Sites easier to use, improve our advertising and to provide you with a more personal and convenient experience.  For example, we may use this information to store some of your preferences or to provide you with tailored advertisements related to your specific interests on our Sites and other sites, [and across your different devices].  Additionally, should you choose to enroll, we and our partners may use this information to allow you to participate in one of our fan rewards programs.  To learn more about the use of cookies in online advertising, including how to manage or delete them [click here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/learn_more.asp).

We and some of our partners use Flash cookies to store some of your preferences or personal information.  For more information on Flash cookies and how to manage privacy and storage settings [click here](http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager.html).

In some of our email messages, we use “click-through URLs” or pixel tags to determine whether the email has been opened and to measure the effectiveness of our customer communications.  This data may also be used to gauge your interest in particular topics, so we can deliver a more relevant, personal and convenient user-experience.

**Security**

The security of your personal information is important to us.  When you enter sensitive information on our order forms, we encrypt the transmission of that information using industry accepted security practices.  If you choose to use another company’s payment option to pay for your order, its privacy statement and security practices will apply to your information.  We encourage you to read that privacy statement before providing your information.

We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and after receipt.  However, no method of transmission over the Internet or method of electronic storage is 100% secure and we cannot guarantee its absolute security.  If you have any questions about the security of your personal information, you can contact us by clicking here.

**Accessing/Updating Your Personal Information**

Upon request we will provide you with information about whether we hold any of your personal information.

Our Sites may offer different methods for updating your personal information.  To review and update your personal information on artist marketing Sites, please log in to your profile/account on each Site where you have registered.  If the Site does not have a profile/account page, you may review and update your personal information by [clicking here](https://www.sonymusic.com/feedback/).

If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services, contact us by [clicking here](https://www.sonymusic.com/feedback/). 

We will respond to your requests within a reasonable timeframe.

**Consent to Processing**

Our Sites are operated in the United States.  If you are located in the European Union, Canada or elsewhere outside of the United States, please be aware that information we collect will be transferred to and processed in the United States. By using our Sites, or providing us with any information, you fully understand and consent to this transfer, processing and storage of your information in the United States, a jurisdiction in which the privacy laws may not be as comprehensive as those in the country where you reside and/or are a citizen.

**Additional Information**

Links to Other Site(s) – Our Site(s) includes links to other site(s) whose privacy practices may differ from those of Sony Music.  If you submit personal information to any of those sites, your information is governed by their privacy policies.  We encourage you to carefully read the privacy policy of any site you visit.

Children – We do not knowingly collect or attempt to collect any personal information from children under the age of 13.  If you feel that we have unknowingly collected information from someone under the age of 13, please [contact us](https://www.sonymusic.com/feedback/) immediately and this information will be removed.

For more information on how to protect your children online:

**Visit  **[ **www.OnGuardOnline.gov**](http://www.onguardonline.gov/) **  for social networking safety tips for **[ **parents**](http://www.onguardonline.gov/topics/social-networking-sites.aspx) **  and **[ **youth**](http://www.onguardonline.gov/topics/safety-tips-tweens-teens.aspx) **.**

**Changes To This Policy**

By using our Site(s), you agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy.  We may amend this Privacy Policy at any time and, as such, we encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.  If we make a material change to this Privacy Policy, we will send an email to users who have provided an email address or post a notice on our Site(s) prior to the change becoming effective.  

**Additional Information for California Residents**

In addition to the information provided above regarding the categories, sources, uses, and sharing of personal information we collect, we are providing the following additional information to California residents consistent with applicable law.  

We collect the information described above (including identifiers, commercial information, internet or other electronic network activity, and geolocation data) from fans and consumers, artists, business partners, other applications (e.g., social networks), advertising networks and digital service providers.  We may use this information for any of the business purposes described above.  We may also share this information with the following categories of third parties: Sony Music and affiliated companies, artists, advertising networks, digital service providers and other business partners for such business purposes. 

In addition to the sources and categories of third parties mentioned above, we also may share this information with law enforcement and professional service companies for the limited purposes of addressing our compliance and legal obligations and exercising our legal rights.

_California Consumer Rights_

Subject to certain exceptions, California residents have the following rights: (i)  _Access and portability_.  Upon a verifiable request, California residents can request access to specific pieces of personal information that we collect, use, disclose or sell and information about our data practices; (ii)  _Deletion_.  Request deletion of your personal information; and (iii)  _opt out of sharing with third parties for certain commercial purposes._  To the extent permitted by applicable law, we may be required to retain some of your personal information, and certain personal information is strictly necessary in order for us to fulfil the purposes described in this Privacy Policy.

_Do Not Sell My Personal Information_

We do not sell your personal information to third parties for money.  However, we share personal information with other companies and service providers in compliance with the law in order to deliver more meaningful ads and other communications to consumers, and for other similar reasons provided in this policy. 

California residents have the right to opt-out of this information sharing.  If you wish to exercise this right, please [click here](https://www.sonymusic.com/ccpa-contact-form/) or call the following toll-free number  _[_ 1-833-380-0676 _]_.  To the extent that you elect to designate an authorized agent to make a request on your behalf, they must select “An Authorized Representative” on the form _.  _ We will not share the personal information of California minors who are under the age of 16 with third parties for commercial purposes without affirmative consent, which can be provided at the point of data collection.

_Exercising other California Consumer Rights_

If you are a California resident and wish to exercise any of these rights, please: (a) contact us [here](https://www.sonymusic.com/feedback/) with the specific nature of your request, referencing “Your California Privacy Rights”; or call the following toll-free number  _[_ 1-833-380-0676 _]_.  When submitting your request, you must affirm that you are a California resident or an authorized representative for a California resident.  Authorized agents must be registered with the California Secretary of State, and the consumer must designate the authorized agent by providing the authorized agent with a valid power of attorney or written permission to act for the consumer.  All requests should be properly labelled and contain all the necessary information.  You may be asked to provide additional proof of identification so that we can verify your identity and validate the request.  Please note that you are limited by law in the number of requests you may submit per year.  We will not discriminate against you by offering you different pricing or products, or by providing you with a different level or quality of products, based solely upon you exercising your rights under the CCPA. 

_California “Shine the Light”_

If you are a California resident, California Civil Code Section 1798.83 provides you the right to receive (a) information identifying any third party(ies) to whom we may have disclosed, within the preceding calendar year, your personal information for that third party’s direct marketing purposes; and (b) a description of the categories of personal information disclosed.  To obtain such information free of charge, please write to us at the address below, or submit your request here. We will respond to these requests within thirty (30) days.  Requests that come to us by other means may result in a delayed response.

**Questions About This Privacy Policy**

If you have questions or concerns regarding this Privacy Policy, you should first contact Sony Music. You can contact us about this Privacy Policy by writing us:

ATTN: Sony Music Privacy Office  
Sony Music Entertainment 25 Madison Avenue, 22nd Floor  
New York, NY 10010

Or you can [click here](https://www.sonymusic.com/feedback/) to submit feedback online.

If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at <https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request>.
